A Guide to the Margaret Hoffman Collection, 1893-1969
Shenandoah County Library
Shenandoah County Library
Margaret Hoffman Collection, 1893-1969
Shenandoah County Library
2019-0001
This collection has been digitized and is available online.
6 boxes, 203 folders
A collection of photographs, letters, and ephemera collected by Margaret V. Hoffman. The majority of items date to the 1930s and 1940s. Many are related to Camp Strawderman which Margaret helped operate.
Margaret V. Hoffman
Administrative Information
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open to researchers without restrictions. Researchers must register and agree to all copyright laws and archives policies before using the collection. Please contact the Shenandoah County Library before visiting to use this collection.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from the estate of Marguerite Ritenour Hoffman July 25 2018.
Rights Statement for Archival Description
Creative Commons Attribution-Non Commercial (CC-BY-NC)
Biographical/Historical Note
Margaret V. Hoffman (1889-1986) was the founder of Camp Strawderman, a recreational camp for girls in the Columbia Furnace section of Shenandoah County west of Edinburg. Her father had inherited the farm that is now the camp and she began bringing friends to the area in 1917. In 1929 the camp was officially founded and she remained its director for over 50 years. She grew up in Woodstock Virginia and attended the Women's College of Frederick Maryland. Her parents were Dr. Samuel Joseph Hoffman and Margaret Virginia Rinker Hoffman.
Her niece Margaret V. Hoffman Gouldman (1922-) is the current owner of the camp. She grew up in Woodstock Virginia and attended Madison College (now James Madison University).
Sources:
"Our Story," Camp Strawderman, accessed January 10 2019, https://campstrawderman.com/about/our-story/.
Stickley, Judy Coffman. Someone You Knew II, Shenandoah County Virginia Necrology 1869-1989, Volume I. Self-Published, compiled 1997. Shenandoah Room, Shenandoah County Library, Edinburg, Virginia, USA.
Scope and Content
The Margaret Hoffman Collection consists of approximately 8 linear feet of material. This includes 160 folders of documents, 48 sleeves of photographs, eight oversize folders, and an assortment of physical objects and class notebooks. They are stored in 3 document cases, a single photograph box, two oversize boxes, and a single oversize folder inside the archive's map case.
The collection is organized into the following five (5) series:
Series I: Correspondence consisting of letters sent by Margaret V. Hoffman (Gouldman) while living in Woodstock and while attending Madison College in Harrisonburg Virginia. The correspondence is dated 1916-1955 and is sorted chronologically.
Series II: Document consists of documents from the Hoffman family, activities in Woodstock Virginia, and activities in Harrisonburg Virginia. The documents are dated 1903-1945 and are sorted chronologically.
Series III: Camp Strawderman consists of documents, booklets, and marketing material from Camp Strawderman west of Edinburg Virginia. The materials are dated 1939-ca. 1960 and are sorted chronologically.
Series IV: Photographs consists of photographs primarily showing events and people at Camp Strawderman. The photographs are dated 1930-1947 and are sorted chronologically.
Series V: Notebooks consists of Camp Strawderman related notebooks and those from Margaret V. Hoffman's time at the Women's College of Frederick Maryland. They are dated 1888-1939 and are sorted by size.
Series VI: Objects consists of physical objects from Woodstock Virginia. They are dated ca. 1940 and are sorted by size.
Series VII: Oversize consists of oversize materials, primarily newspapers. They are dated 1893-1969 and are sorted chronologically.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into seven (7) series:
Series I: Correspondence, 1916-1955
Box 1: Stack 9, Shelf 3 38758101509411
Box 2: Stack 9, Shelf 3 38758101509403
Series II: Documents, 1903-1945
Box 3: Stack 9, Shelf 3 38758101509395
Series III: Camp Strawderman, 1939- ca. 1960
Box 3: Stack 9, Shelf 3 38758101509395
Series IV: Photographs, 1930-1947
Box 3: Stack 9, Shelf 3 38758101509395
Box 4: Stack 9, Shelf 3 3875801509387
Series V: Notebooks, 1888-1939
Box 5: Stack 3, Shelf 7 38758101509379
Series VI: Objects, ca. 1940
Box 5: Stack 3, Shelf 7 38758101509379
Series VII: Oversize, 1893-1969
Box 6: Stack 2, Shelf 5 38758101509361
OVERSIZE FOLDER 1 Map Case Drawer D, Folder 19 38758101161080
Index Terms
Persons:
Hoffman, Margaret V. (1889-1986)
Contents List
- Series I: Correspondence, 1916-1955
  - (Box 1)
    - Alumnae Banquet, State Normal School, Harrisonburg Virginia, "Miss Hoffman", June 5 1916 (Folder 1.1)
    - Postcards, Paul to Margaret Hoffman, Woodstock Virginia, February 1933 (Folder 1.2)
    - Postcard, Chester to Margaret Hoffman, Camp Strawderman, June 24, 1937 (Folder 1.3)
    - Letters, "Pinkie" to Margaret Hoffman, Woodstock Virginia, September – October 1937 (Folder 1.4)
    - Postcard, "Mrs. C.E. Ketz" Grantsville Maryland to Margaret Hoffman, Woodstock, Virginia, September 6 1937 (Folder 1.5)
    - "Polly" to Margaret Hoffman, Woodstock Virginia, September 8 1937 (Folder 1.6)
    - Letter, "Edith Farr" to Margaret Hoffman, October 2 1937 (Folder 1.7)
    - : Letter, "Dad" (Dr. McC. Hoffman) to Margaret Hoffman, Woodstock Virginia, December 13 1937 (Folder 1.8)
    - Letters, "Pat" to Margaret Hoffman, Woodstock Virginia, 1937 (Folder 1.9)
    - Letters from William Holliday, Leeds/York England to Margaret Hoffman, Woodstock Virginia, 1937 (Folder 1.10)
    - Letters, "Patsy Maphis" to Margaret Hoffman, Camp Strawderman, June – September 1938 (Folder 1.11)
    - , Letters, "Finley" to Margaret Hoffman, Woodstock VirginiaJuly – August 1938 (Folder 1.12)
    - Letter, "Milly" to Margaret Hoffman, Camp Strawderman, July 1, 1938 (Folder 1.13)
    - Postcard, Finley to Margaret Hoffman, Camp Strawderman, July 4 1938 (Folder 1.14)
    - Letter, "Vivian" to Margaret Hoffman, July 12, 1938 (Folder 1.15)
    - Letters, "Charlotte" to Margaret Hoffman, Camp Strawderman, July 1938 (Folder 1.16)
    - Postcard, "Pinkie" to Margaret Hoffman, Camp Strawderman, August 2 1938 (Folder 1.17)
    - Letter, "Peggy" to Margaret Hoffman, Camp Strawderman, August 22 1938 (Folder 1.18)
    - Letter, "Betty" to Margaret Hoffman, Woodstock Virginia, September 8 1938 (Folder 1.19)
    - Letter, "Me" to Margaret Hoffman, Woodstock Virginia, September 28, 1938 (Folder 1.20)
    - Letter "Sam Banks" to Margaret Hoffman, November 8 1938 (Folder 1.21)
    - : Letters. "Polly Jo McCullach" (Berkley West Virginia) to Margaret Hoffman, Woodstock Virginia, August – November 1938 (Folder 1.22)
    - New Year Card, "Quentin" to Margaret Hoffman, Woodstock Virginia, December 20 1938 (Folder 1.23)
    - Christmas Card, "Jackson" to Margaret Hoffman, Woodstock Virginia, December 21, 1938 (Folder 1.24)
    - Letters, "Bill" (Leeds England), to Margaret Hoffman, Woodstock Virginia, 1938 (Folder 1.25)
    - Letters, "Nic" (Virginia Polytechnic Institute) to Margaret Hoffman, 1938 (Folder 1.26)
    - Letters, "Judy" to Margaret Hoffman, Camp Strawderman, 1938 (Folder 1.27)
    - Madison College Correspondence with Margaret Hoffman, 1938-1941 (Folder 1.28)
    - Graduation Card, "Ann and Sonny" to Margaret Hoffman, June 2, 1939 (Folder 1.29)
    - Post Card, Douglas V Evans to Margaret Hoffman, June 29 1939 (Folder 1.30)
    - Postcard, "Nic" to Margaret Hoffman, Woodstock Virginia, March 6 1939 (Folder 1.31)
    - Postcard, "Brenda" to Margaret Hoffman, Camp Strawderman, August 24 1939 (Folder 1.32)
    - Postcard, "Ed" to Margaret Hoffman, Orkney Springs Virginia, September 12 1939 (Folder 1.33)
    - Letters from William Holliday, Leeds/York England to Margaret Hoffman, Woodstock Virginia, 1939 (Folder 1.34)
    - Letters, "Nic" (Virginia Polytechnic Institute) to Margaret Hoffman, Woodstock Virginia, 1939 (Folder 1.35)
    - Letters, "Pat" to Margaret Hoffman, Woodstock Virginia, 1939 (Folder 1.36)
    - Letter, "Judy" and V___ Virginia Fish" to Margaret Hoffman, Camp Strawderman, 1939 (Folder 1.37)
    - Letters, "Finley Shields", to Margaret Hoffman, June-December 1939 (Folder 1.38)
    - Letter, "Sonny" (Carlisle Pennsylvania) to Margaret Hoffman, Woodstock Virginia, February 26 1939 (Folder 1.39)
    - Letter, Dud Wright of St. Louis Missouri to Margaret Hoffman, Woodstock Virginia, March 25, 1939 (Folder 1.40)
    - Letter, "Orange Smit" to Margaret Hoffman, Camp Strawderman, June 15 1939 (Folder 1.41)
    - Letter, "Charlotte" to Margaret Hoffman, Camp Strawderman, June 26 1939 (Folder 1.42)
    - Letter, "Edith" to Margaret Hoffman, Camp Strawderman, June 28 1939 (Folder 1.43)
    - Letter, JJ. Johnson" to Pat Maphis and Margaret Hoffman, Camp Strawderman, July 6, 1939 (Folder 1.44)
    - Letter, "Quentin" to Margaret Hoffman, Camp Strawderman, July 18 1939 (Folder 1.45)
    - Letters, "PJ"to Margaret Hoffman, Camp Strawderman, August 22 – 30, 1939 (Folder 1.46)
    - Letter, "Sam" to Margaret Hoffman, Madison College, September 25 1939 (Folder 1.47)
    - Letters to Margaret Hoffman, August 23 1939 (Folder 1.48)
    - Letter, Judy Johnson to Margaret Hoffman, September 11 1939 (Folder 1.49)
  - (Box 2)
    - Letter, "Finley" (Hampden Sydney College) to Margaret Hoffman, Madison College, February 8, 1940 (Folder 2.1)
    - Unsigned Card sent to Margaret Hoffman, Madison College, February 12, 1940 (Folder 2.2)
    - Valentine Card from "Jo" to Margaret Hoffman, Woodstock Virginia, February 13, 1940 (Folder 2.3)
    - Valentine Card, "Quentin S." to Margaret Hoffman, Madison College, February 1940 (Folder 2.4)
    - : Letters, "Judy" to Margaret Hoffman, Madison College, February – April 1940 (Folder 2.5)
    - Letters, "Pat" to Margaret Hoffman, Woodstock Virginia, May – August 1940 (Folder 2.6)
    - Postcard, "Nellie" to Margaret Hoffman, Woodstock Virginia, June 11 1940 (Folder 2.7)
    - "Margaret Aitken" to Margaret Hoffman, Camp Strawderman, June 25, 1940 (Folder 2.8)
    - Letter, "Bill" (Leeds England) to Margaret Hoffman, Camp Strawderman, June 30 1940 (Folder 2.9)
    - Letter, "T Box" to Margaret Hoffman, Camp Strawderman, July 6, 1940 (Folder 2.10)
    - Letters, "PJ" to Margaret Hoffman, Woodstock Virginia, August – September 1940 (Folder 2.11)
    - "Sappy" to Margaret Hoffman, Camp Strawderman, August 26 1940 (Folder 2.12)
    - "Jeane" to Margaret Hoffman, Woodstock Virginia, September 3 1940 (Folder 2.13)
    - Patricia Maphis, Bethesda Chevy Chase High School Graduation Announcement, 1940 (Folder 2.14)
    - Graduation Announcement, Judith Johnson, Woodstock High School, 1940 (Folder 2.15)
    - : Letter "Douglas V Evans (Principal Woodstock High School) to Margaret Hoffman, Madison College, January 26 1941 (Folder 2.16)
    - Letter, "Banca" (Camp Strawderman) to Eddie Williams, Harrisonburg Virginia, February 8 1941 (Folder 2.17)
    - Letter, "Pat Maphis" to Margaret Hoffman, Woodstock Virginia, February 26 1941 (Folder 2.18)
    - Letters, "Chubby" to Margaret Hoffman, June – July 1941 (Folder 2.19)
    - Telegram and letter, "PJ" to Margaret Hoffman, Camp Strawderman, June 1941 (Folder 2.20)
    - Letter, "Sappy" to Margaret Hoffman, Camp Strawderman, July 9 1941 (Folder 2.21)
    - Letter, "Marg" to Margaret Hoffman, Camp Strawderman, July 19 1941 (Folder 2.22)
    - Letter, "Jeannie" to Margaret Hoffman, Camp Strawderman, August 15 1941 (Folder 2.23)
    - Letter, "Betty Sanford to Margaret Hoffman, Woodstock Virginia, August 27 1941 (Folder 2.24)
    - Letters, "Val" to Margaret Hoffman, Woodstock Virginia, August – October 1942 (Folder 2.25)
    - Letter, "Mother" to Margaret Hoffman, Madison College, October 13 1942 (Folder 2.26)
    - Letter, "Kelly" to Margaret Hoffman, Madison College, October 26 1942 (Folder 2.27)
    - Letters, "Pat" to Margaret Hoffman, Woodstock Virginia, November 16 1942 (Folder 2.28)
    - Christmas Card, "Charlie" to Margaret Hoffman, December 17 1942 (Folder 2.29)
    - Invitation, "Mrs. Benchoff's Music Class", Christmas Program, December 21 1942 (Folder 2.30)
    - Christmas Card, "Jappy" to Margaret Hoffman, Woodstock Virginia, December 24 1942 (Folder 2.31)
    - Letters, "CE Keltz" to Margaret Hoffman, Madison College, January – April 1943 (Folder 2.32)
    - Letter, "Val" to Margaret Hoffman, Delta House Madison College, January 10 1943 (Folder 2.33)
    - Letter, "Samuel Hoffman" to Margaret Hoffman, Madison College, January 17 1943 (Folder 2.34)
    - Letter, "Walter T Cline" to Margaret Hoffman, Madison College, January 21 1943 (Folder 2.35)
    - Letters, "Charles B Snyder" to Margaret Hoffman, Madison College, January-March 1943 (Folder 2.36)
    - Letter, "Chester Foster" to Margaret Hoffman, Madison College, February 7 1943 (Folder 2.37)
    - Letters, "Harry Getner" to Margaret Hoffman, Madison College, March – May 1943 (Folder 2.38)
    - Letter, "Pat" to Margaret Hoffman, Madison College, April 21 1943 (Folder 2.39)
    - Letters, "Helen" to Margaret Hoffman, Camp Strawderman, June – August 1943 (Folder 2.40)
    - Postcards, Jean to Margaret Hoffman, Camp Strawderman, August – September 1943 (Folder 2.41)
    - Postcard, Brodwin Piano Co, Inc, to Camp Strawderman, 1955 (Folder 2.42)
    - Letters, "Patsy" (Patricia Maphis) to Margaret Hoffman, Undated (Folder 2.43)
    - Letter, "M ___Johnson" to Margaret Hoffman, Camp Strawderman, Undated (Folder 2.44)
    - Letter, "Walt" to Margaret Hoffman, Undated (Folder 2.45)
    - Letter to Margaret Hoffman, Undated (Folder 2.46)
    - Letter, "Mom" to Margaret Hoffman, Undated (Folder 2.47)
    - Christmas Card, "Brownie" to Margaret Hoffman, Undated (Folder 2.48)
    - Birthday Cards sent to Margaret Hoffman, Undated (Folder 2.49)
- Series II: Documents, 1903-1945
  - (Box 3)
    - Virginia Polytechnic Institute Report for Paul Hoffman, March 6 1903 (Folder 3.1)
    - Shenandoah National Bank Checks, "Hoffman and Hildebrant", 1911 (Folder 3.2)
    - Cassia Lodge, A.I.&A.M., Woodstock Virginia, Paul Hoffman Membership Documents, 1911 (Folder 3.3)
    - Services During Week of Prayer, Churches of Woodstock, January 7-12 1912 (Folder 3.4)
    - University of Virginia Glee Club Performance, Harrisonburg Virginia, February 9 1912 (Folder 3.5)
    - "The Record" Newspaper, Reformed Church, Woodstock Charge, March – June 1912 (Folder 3.6)
    - Massanutten Academy Play Bills, June 1912 (Folder 3.7)
    - Margaret Hoffman Confirmation Certificate, St. Paul's Reform Church, Woodstock Virginia, October 13 1922 (Folder 3.8)
    - Margaret Hoffman, McDowell County West Virginia Report Card, 1929-1930 (Folder 3.9)
    - Landon Stickley Electrical Contractor Invoice, Woodstock Virginia, November 12 1929 (Folder 3.10)
    - Eddie Williams Checks, Woodstock National and Shenandoah National Bank, 1931-1933 (Folder 3.11)
    - Margaret Hoffman 5th and 6th Grade Report Cards, Woodstock Graded School, 1932-1934 (Folder 3.12)
    - Woodstock High School "Sez Who" Newspapers, November 4 1936 – June 2 1937 (Folder 3.13)
    - Randolph-Macon Academy Commencement Program, Front Royal Virginia, May 30-June 3 1937 (Folder 3.14)
    - "La Tour" Woodstock High School Newspaper, October 7 1937 – June 3 1938 (Folder 3.15)
    - St. Paul's Evangelical and Reformed Church Choir Concert, Woodstock Virginia, January 26 1938 (Folder 3.16)
    - "Miss Virginia Haslett, Piano Fortte Recital," Methodist Episcopal Church South, Woodstock Virginia, June 17 1938 (Folder 3.17)
    - "La Tour" and "School Daze" Woodstock High School Newspapers, September 1938-June 1939 (Folder 3.18)
    - Shenandoah County Bank and Trust Company Calendar, Woodstock Virginia, 1939 (Folder 3.19)
    - "Here Comes Charlie", Woodstock High School Senior Class Production, Community Theater, February 6 1939 (Folder 3.20)
    - "Waiting", Margaret Hoffman Essay, Madison College English 133, May 3 1940 (Folder 3.21)
    - Woodstock High School, Class of 1941 Commencement Announcement (Folder 3.22)
    - Pennsylvania Railroad Ticket, New York to Washington DC, January 1942 (Folder 3.23)
    - Check, Eddie Williams, Shenandoah Bank and Trust, February 12 1944 (Folder 3.24)
    - Invitation to Massanutten Military Academy Thirteenth Annual Formal Military Ball Sent to "Mrs. Keltz", February 24 1945 (Folder 3.25)
    - "Rip Van Winkle" Story by Stella Rinker, Undated (Folder 3.26)
    - "Dogs" A Margaret Hoffman Composition, Undated (Folder 3.27)
    - Scrapbook pages, Undated (Folder 3.28)
    - Margaret Revere Hoffman, Madison College and Woodstock Virginia Envelopes, Undated (Folder 3.29)
    - Margaret Hoffman French Schoolwork, Undated (Folder 3.30)
    - Haun-Magruder Insurance Agency, Citizens Insurance Company Flyer, Undated (Folder 3.31)
    - The William Kline Company, Jewelers and Opticians, Woodstock Virginia, Undated (Folder 3.32)
    - Mable's Beauty Salon, Harrisonburg Virginia, Run Arrestors, Undated (Folder 3.33)
- Series III: Camp Strawderman, 1939- ca. 1960
  - (Box 3)
    - "Strawderman Echo", 1939 (Folder 3.34)
    - Camp Strawderman Booklet, 1940 (Folder 3.35)
    - "Strawderman Echo", 1940 (Folder 3.36)
    - "Yoio Hoo" Camp Strawderman Document, July 6 1941 (Folder 3.37)
    - Camp Strawderman Booklet, 1942 (Folder 3.38)
    - "Strawderman Echo", 1942 (Folder 3.39)
    - Camp Strawderman Songbook, 1944 (Folder 3.40)
    - Camp Strawderman Booklet, 1950 (Folder 3.41)
    - Camp Strawderman Booklet, 1955 (Folder 3.42)
    - Camp Strawderman Booklet, 1956 (Folder 3.43)
    - Camp Strawderman Booklet, ca 1960 (Folder 3.44)
    - Camp Strawderman Booklet, ca 1960 (Folder 3.45)
    - Camp Strawderman Christmas Greetings, Undated (Folder 3.46)
    - Camp Strawderman Statement and Card, Undated (Folder 3.47)
    - Camp Strawderman Candlelight Service, Undated (Folder 3.48)
    - Camp Strawderman Envelopes and Stationary, Undated (Folder 3.49)
- Series IV: Photographs, 1930-1947
  - (Box 3)
    - "Camp Strawderman Presents "We Are America!", Undated (Folder 3.50)
    - "Seasons Greetings", Camp Strawderman Postcard, Undated (Folder 3.51)
    - "Hillcrest Madison College", Postcard, Mr. and Mrs. G. Tyler Miller, Undated (Folder 3.52)
    - Color Photograph, Camp Strawderman barn, Undated (Folder 3.53)
    - Photograph of Unidentified House, Undated (Folder 3.54)
  - (Box 4)
    - Camp Strawderman Photographs, September 19 1930 (Sleeve 4.1)
    - Camp Strawderman Photographic Postcards, 1 of 3, ca. 1945 (Sleeve 4.2)
    - Camp Strawderman Photographic Postcards, 2 of 3, ca. 1945 (Sleeve 4.3)
    - Camp Strawderman Photographic Postcards, 3 of 3, ca. 1945 (Sleeve 4.4)
    - Camp Strawderman. Color Photographs, February 24 1947 (Sleeve 4.5)
    - Unidentified Family, July 1959 (Sleeve 4.6)
    - Camp Strawderman Photographs, Workers, Buildings and Campers, 1 of 3, Undated (Sleeve 4.7)
    - Camp Strawderman Photographs, Workers, Buildings and Campers, 2 of 3, Undated (Sleeve 4.8)
    - Camp Strawderman Photographs, Workers, Buildings and Campers, 3 of 3, Undated (Sleeve 4.9)
    - Unidentified Women and Boy, Camp Strawderman Undated (Sleeve 4.10)
    - Camp Strawderman Photographs "15", Undated (Sleeve 4.11)
    - Camp Strawderman Photographs, 1 of 3, Undated (Sleeve 4.12)
    - Camp Strawderman Photographs, 2 of 3, Undated (Sleeve 4.13)
    - Camp Strawderman Photographs, 3 of 3, Undated (Sleeve 4.14)
    - Camp Strawderman, Girls on Horseback, Undated (Sleeve 4.15)
    - Unidentified Woman, Undated (Sleeve 4.16)
    - Unidentified Woman, Undated (Sleeve 4.16)
    - Camp Strawderman Photographs, "64", 1 of 2, Undated (Sleeve 4.18)
    - Camp Strawderman Photographs, "64", 2 of 2, Undated (Sleeve 4.19)
    - Camp Strawderman Photographs, "28", 1 of 2, Undated (Sleeve 4.20)
    - Camp Strawderman Photographs, "28", 2 of 2, Undated (Sleeve 4.21)
    - Camp Strawderman Photographs, "24", 1 of 3, Undated (Sleeve 4.22)
    - Camp Strawderman Photographs, "24", 2 of 3, Undated (Sleeve 4.23)
    - Camp Strawderman Photographs, "24", 3 of 3, Undated (Sleeve 4.24)
    - Unidentified Girls, Swimming at Camp Strawderman, Undated (Sleeve 4.25)
    - Unidentified Woman at Camp Strawderman, Undated (Sleeve 4.26)
    - Camp Strawderman Horse Riding Photographs, Undated (Sleeve 4.27)
    - Camp Strawderman Swimming Photographs, 1 of 2, Undated (Sleeve 4.28)
    - Camp Strawderman Swimming Photographs, 2 of 2, Undated (Sleeve 4.29)
    - Unidentified Woman in Body of Water, Undated (Sleeve 4.30)
    - Stella Rinker Relation Photographs, Undated (Sleeve 4.31)
    - Camp Strawderman Activities, 1 of 2, Undated (Sleeve 4.32)
    - Camp Strawderman Activities, 2 of 2, Undated (Sleeve 4.33)
    - Camp Strawderman Photographs, 1 of 3, Undated (Sleeve 4.34)
    - Camp Strawderman Photographs, 2 of 3, Undated (Sleeve 4.35)
    - Camp Strawderman Photographs, 3 of 3, Undated (Sleeve 4.36)
    - Unidentified Camp Strawderman, Beazleys Photo Finishing Series Edinburg, VA, 1 of 2, Undated (Sleeve 4.37)
    - Unidentified Camp Strawderman, Beazleys Photo Finishing Series Edinburg, VA, 2 of 2, Undated (Sleeve 4.38)
    - Camp Strawderman Girls with Truck, Undated (Sleeve 4.39)
    - Football Players, Hoffman Family, Undated (Sleeve 4.40)
    - Unidentified Woman, Undated (Sleeve 4.41)
    - Mary Clare Doughanty, Undated (Sleeve 4.42)
    - Camp Strawderman, Water Show, Undated (Sleeve 4.43)
    - Camp Strawderman, REPRODUCTIONS, 1 of 5, Undated (Sleeve 4.44)
    - Camp Strawderman, REPRODUCTIONS, 2 of 5, Undated (Sleeve 4.45)
    - Camp Strawderman, REPRODUCTIONS, 3 of 5, Undated (Sleeve 4.46)
    - Camp Strawderman, REPRODUCTIONS, 4 of 5, Undated (Sleeve 4.47)
    - Camp Strawderman, REPRODUCTIONS, 5 of 5, Undated (Sleeve 4.48)
- Series V: Notebooks, 1888-1939
  - (Box 5)
    - Notebook of Stella M. Rinker, Shenandoah Institute, Woodstock Virginia, September 26 1888
    - Margaret Hoffman, Camp Strawderman Autograph Book, 1939
    - English Literature II Notebook, Margaret Hoffman, Women's College of Frederick Maryland,, February 5, 1906
    - History I Notebook, Margaret Hoffman, Women's College of Frederick Maryland, 1904-1908
    - English Literature Notebook, Margaret Hoffman, Women's College of Frederick Maryland,, September 20 1905
    - English I Notebook, Margaret Hoffman, Women's College of Frederick Maryland, October 20 1904
    - "Margaret Hoffman Normal" Notebook, Women's College of Frederick Maryland, ca. 1905
    - English Literature II, Book III, Margaret Hoffman, Women's College of Frederick Maryland, May 17 1906
    - Unidentified Class Notebook, Margaret Hoffman, Women's College of Frederick Maryland, ca. 1905
    - Unidentified Class Notebook, Margaret Hoffman, Women's College of Frederick Maryland, ca. 1905
- Series VI: Objects, ca. 1940
  - (Box 5)
    - Shoe Horn, Grabill's Shoe Store, Woodstock Virginia Undated
    - Woodstock High School Varsity Letter, ca. 1940
- Series VII: Oversize, 1893-1969
  - (Box 6)
    - Handkerchief, 1893 Chicago Exhibition (Folder 6.1)
    - Irwin Opera House Playbills, Woodstock Virginia, ca. 1900 (Folder 6.2)
    - Calendar, Paul Dellinger Esso Station, Woodstock Virginia, 1937 (Folder 6.3)
    - "Strawderman Horn" Camp Strawderman Newspaper, 1936-1950 (Folder 6.4)
    - "Strawderman Horn" Camp Strawderman Newspaper, 1951-1959 (Folder 6.5)
    - "Strawderman Horn" Camp Strawderman Newspaper, 1960-1964 (Folder 6.6)
    - "Strawderman Horn" Camp Strawderman Newspaper, 1965-1969 (Folder 6.7)
  - (Folder 1)
    - Landscape Photograph, Camp Strawderman Girls Viewing a Mountain Scene, Undated